- 我們這一天 字幕由SSK字幕組傾情譯制 -
- 字幕僅供學習，勿用於商 -
- 轉載請註明出處，版權歸片方所有 -
- 新浪微博@SSK字幕組 官網：www.sskzmz.com -
我們
這
一天
翻譯 小伍
翻譯 Tabby汪
翻譯 summer
校對 Bunny
特效 Bunny
壓制 王祖賢老婆
總監 Bunny
家庭照片
一件有趣的事實：
維基百科顯示，平均每個人都和一千八百萬人分享同一個生日。
然而並沒有證據能夠證明，同一天出生的人之間存在著任何行為的相似性。
如果有....
那就是維基百科還沒發現而已。
每一勺
二百五十卡路里
垃圾
快把這些垃圾扔掉
凱特，不要妄想在你的
派對開始之前動這個蛋糕。
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h愛你的凱特
講真，你有毛病嗎？
好消息
找到他了
姓名：威廉·希爾
年齡：62歲
住址：賓夕法尼亞州 林肯街14號 四號樓B室
特別花絮：「奶爸"在錄製現場發飆
致我最愛的侄女們
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h愛你們的
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h凱文叔叔
好的 我準備好了
Okay, I'm ready.
你保證你會喜歡你的禮物的吧
You promise you like your gift?
這條毛巾嗎 不忍直視
The towel? It's absolutely terrible.
穿好衣服了嗎
Suit's on?
-一切就緒 夫人 -我指的是你的生日套裝
- Yes, ma'am. - Your birthday suit.
永遠都是這件
Only one I've got.
我不得不把內衣穿在外面
I had to put the lingerie on top of my clothes.
我注意到了
I see that.
這讓我感覺糟透了
It wasn't a great moment for me.
生日傳統就是傳統
Tradition is tradition.
好吧 但今年我想直接切入正題
Yeah. But I'm gonna go ahead
省掉火辣生日舞
and spare us both the seductive birthday dance
-的環節 -抱歉 寶貝 但是今天是我的生日
- this year. - I'm sorry, baby, but it's my birthday,
而我真的很想 很想 很想看那支舞
and I would really, really like to see the dance.
等死吧你
Your funeral.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
-準備好了嗎 -嗯哼
- Ready? - Mm-hmm.
你喜歡這樣
You like it,
對嗎
right?
這就是你想要的對吧
This is what you want.
這樣來一點
A little of that.
再這樣來一點
A little of that, for you?
你就等著
I will gag
我用毛巾噎死你吧
you dead with that towel.
好了 好了
Okay, okay.
-我這就閉嘴 -求你了
- I'm quiet. - Come on.
你混蛋
You suck.
老闆 有空嗎
Got a sec, boss?
有啊 怎麼了
Yeah. What's up?
耶
Yeah...
-我們超愛你的節目的 -哈
- We love your show. - Huh?
你想一起來跳舞嗎
Do you want to dance?
額額 不想 但是 嗯
Uh-uh. No. But, um,
你們可以繼續
you know, you go ahead.
今天是我的生日
It's my birthday today.
我今天三十六了
36 today.
-你看起來一點都不像啊 -我超像
- You don't look 36. - Yeah, I do.
嘿 三個寶 你們仨知道
Hey, Big Three, do you three know
我有多愛你們媽媽嗎 我是說 你們真的
how much I love your mother? I mean, do you even have
-知道嗎 -我們當然 現在趕緊閉嘴
- any idea? - Yeah, we do. Now shut up
-放你的大屁股老婆去睡覺好嗎 -不行
- and let your fat-ass wife go to sleep. - No.
不 不 生日傳統就是傳統
No, no, no. Birthday tradition is birthday tradition.
孩子們 閉上你們的小眼睛 因為爸爸要對媽咪
So close your eyes in there, kids, because Daddy's about
做一些非常羞羞的事情
to do some real terrible things to Mommy.
你怎麼會對一個大腹便便的孕婦有性趣
How could you possibly want me right now?
無論何時 我的妻子 你都讓我燃起慾火
In any state, my wife, you arouse me.
我保證我會澆滅它的
I bet I can make that go away.
-你澆不滅的 -我的羊水破了
- There's nothing you can say that's... - My water just broke.
-你做到了 -沒錯
- Yep. - Yeah.
我是在一九八六年的時候發現一切開始偏離正軌的
You know when I think it all went wrong for me was 1986,
那時候我才二年級 他們正準備把挑戰者號送進太空
second grade. They were sending the Challenger up into space.
你們記得挑戰者號 對嗎
You remember the Challenger, right?
-記得 和桑德拉·布洛克一起的 -不
- Yeah. With Sandra Bullock? - No.
是克麗斯塔·麥克利夫對嗎  她當時正要
Christa McAuliffe, right? She was gonna be
成為第一位登上太空的老師
the first teacher into space.
她差點就改變世界了
She was actually gonna change the world.
我雖然對這些事情一竅不通 但是你能感覺到對嗎
I don't know how, but you could feel that, you know?
至少 在二年級的時候 你可以感覺到
At least, in second grade, you could... you could feel it.
那天中午在學校
Middle of the school day,
那個老師出現在電視機裏 對嗎
the teacher brings in a TV, right?
我們全部都坐在那兒 看著現場直播
We're all just sitting there, watching the launch,
一大堆七年級在那 只是看著
a bunch of seven-year-olds just-just watchin'.
然後突然之間 彭
And all of a sudden, boom!
所有的東西都炸飛了
The whole thing explodes.
小老師克麗斯塔·麥考利夫的碎片
Little pieces of sweet Christa McAuliffe
像雨一樣落在弗洛裏達州的大地上
come raining down all over the state of Florida.
太讓人悲傷了
It was awful.
也許就是在那個時候 我意識到改變世界的最終
Maybe that's when I realized trying to change the world
結果只能是把自己炸成
just leads to being blown up
弗洛裏達州上空漂浮著的小碎片
into little pieces all over Florida.
可能這就是我淪為到演《奶爸》的原因
Maybe that's how I wound up as the Man-ny.
是我姐
It's my sister.
凱特
Kate?
我沒找到冰塊 所以
You... you didn't have any ice, so...
好吧 最糟的時刻
Well, this is a low point.
咱們三十六歲了
We're 36.
我們正式步入三十歲的後期了
We're officially late 30s.
像是 被甩在三十歲的尾巴上了
Like, we are deep in the threes.
沒錯
Yep.
我們怎麼到這一步的
How did I get here?
我他媽到底怎麼變成現在這個樣子的
Like, how the hell did I get here?
還記二年級的時候 挑戰者號爆炸事件嗎
Remember second grade, the Challenger explosion?
別再提那件事了
You have got to stop with the Challenger explosion.
那是一個轉折點
There's something there.
你是我人生裏唯一的好事 凱文
You're the only good thing in my life, Kev.
-少來了 我才沒有那麼好  -我知道
-I'm not that great. Come on. -I know.
這讓我的生活更顯得糟糕
That's what makes it worse.
我曾經有過
I had this...
對自己人生的夢想
whole dream life that I envisioned for myself.
有一份真正的事業
A real career.
嫁一個像老爸那樣的男人
I would marry a man like Dad.
成為像老媽一樣的女人
I would be a mom like Mom.
但是看看我 凱文
But look at me, Kev.
我把我的夢想吃沒了
Like, I ate my dream life away.
所以 你想我對你說什麼呢
So what do you... what do you want me to say to you, huh?
姐 有沒有那種能讓你感到安慰的
Wh-What... Give me the magic phrase, sis, to say
魔咒 如果有我一定會說出來
to make you feel better and I'll say it.
我也不知道 你可以告訴我別再自怨自艾了
Tell me to quit feeling sorry for myself. I don't know.
或者是叫我別做夢了
Tell me to wake the hell up.
叫我下狠心去減肥
Tell me, tell me to lose the damn weight.
別再自怨自艾了
Quit feeling sorry for yourself.
好嗎 就從現在開始 從你的白日夢裏醒過來
All right? That can start right now. Wake the hell up.
還有 你知道的
And-and, you know...
呃 第三件 第三件事情是什麼來著
the... What was the... what was the third thing?
減掉這該死的肥
Lose the damn weight.
你想再說一遍嗎
You want to say that again?
我會減掉這該死的肥的
I'm gonna lose the damn weight.
你比你看起來聰明多了
You are a lot smarter than you look.
邁克爾·貝也是這麼說我的
That's what Michael Bay told me.
-就是這樣 -噢 耶
- Here you go. - Oh, yeah.
謝謝你
Thank you.
嘿 不知道你意識到沒有 孩子們和我
Hey, do you realize me and the kids
-可以同一天過生日了 -我知道
- are gonna have the same birthday? - I know.
耶
Yeah.
提前了六周
Still, six weeks early
-還是太早了 -沒錯
- is pretty early. - Yeah.
我知道
I know.
這玩意兒到底是怎麼用的
What the hell could this thing possibly be for?
這是用來做肛門檢查的
It's for rectal examinations.
你拿的是用過的
That one's from the dirty pile.
不好意思
Sorry.
請容我自我介紹 我是可塔斯基醫生
Now, then, I'm Dr. Katowski,
但是你也可以叫我醫生或是K醫生
but you can call me Doc or Dr. K,
大家通常都是這麼叫我的
which is what most people choose to do
-因為這樣叫比較隨意 -噢
- because it's folksy. - Oh,
你是和施耐德醫生一起工作嗎
so you work with Dr. Schneider?
呼一口氣 親愛的
Take a breath for me, dear.
現在 做深呼吸
Deep breath, now.
幹得好
There you go.
好了 覺得輕鬆點了嗎 很好 很好
All right. You relaxed? Good, good, good.
施耐德醫生的爛尾一個小時之前
Dr. Schneider's appendix burst
破裂了 他剛剛被推進手術室 不 不
an hour ago. He just went into surgery. -No, no,
別慌 別慌 看著我
no, no, no. Now, stay with me.
噢 上帝啊 不 我需要施耐德醫生
Oh, God. No, I need Dr. Schneider
-因為他知道我 -看著我
- 'cause he knows about... - Stay with me now.
在施耐德痛苦掙扎的間隙
Between his screams of agony, Schneider
他向我詳細說明了你的情況
brought me up to speed on everything concerning your case.
我對三胞胎瞭如指掌 並且也知道
I know all about these triplets, and I know that this
-這是一次風險極高的分娩 -沒錯
- is a high-risk pregnancy. - Yeah.
但是一切都會沒事的
But everything's gonna be all right.
你們是在開玩笑
This is some kind of bad joke,
-對吧 -不好意思 這是事實
-right? -It is not, unfortunately.
現在 親愛的 我要直接打消你最大的擔憂
Now, sweetheart, I'm gonna get straight to your first concern.
看著我 看著我
Look at me now. Look at me.
-你看見我了嗎 一個七十三歲的老頭 -沒錯
- Do you see me? I am 73 years old. - Yeah.
-你知道這意味著什麼嗎 -不懂
- You know what that means, don't you? - No.
這意味著我不會像以前一樣火急火燎
That means I don't run wind sprints as fast as I used to,
但我的能力卻依舊老道熟練
but my faculties are otherwise completely intact.
我也曾希望我自己今不如昔
There are days that I wish they weren't,
那樣我就能愉快地享受退休生活 把餘生浪費在比
because then I would retire and spend my remaining days
將一個八磅重的物體從女人的陰道裏拉出來
doing something more glamorous than pulling eight-pound objects
更有吸引力的事情上
out of women's vaginas.
但是直到現在
But until that time,
我依舊每天到這裏報道
I keep showing up here every day.
好了
All right?
我也意識到 於你而言我完全是一個陌生人
I'm also aware that I'm a complete stranger to you,
而此刻是你人生最重要
and this is the biggest moment
-的一刻 -沒錯
- of your life. - Yeah.
-好了 親愛的 聽我說 -好的
- All right? Honey, listen to me, - Yeah.
我是萬里挑一的醫生
I am the best of the best.
而我以我子孫後代的生命
And I swear to you, on the lives of my children
向你擔保 我一定能夠勝任
and my grandchildren, that I am up to the task.
-好嗎 -好的
- All right? All right. - Okay.
-謝謝你 -沒事的
- Thank you. - All right.
很好
Good.
現在 告訴我你們誰懷孕了
Now, which one of you's pregnant?
哈哈 這才是一個冷笑話 但是
Now, that was a bad joke, but
你需要繼續做深呼吸
you just continue to take those deep breaths...
讓我們看看 我的人是不是在周圍
Let's see... let me see if any of my people are here.
讓我們做一個小測試
Let me take a little test. Sheket bevakasha!
猶太人 猶太人
Jew! Jew!
猶太人
Jew!
好了 嘿 拜託
All right, hey! Come on!
現在 開始
And... action!
哈 哈
Huh? Huh?
你想讓我做些什麼來取悅你 哈
What can I do to make you feel better, huh?
需要我給你餵奶 來讓你感覺好點嗎
You want me to breastfeed you? Would that make you feel better,
要我給你餵奶嗎
if I breastfed ya?
沒錯是嗎 好的 來試試
Yeah? Here we go. Let's try to...
對不起 夥計們 我需要停一下 呃
I'm-I'm sorry, guys. I need to cut. Uh...
抱歉 大傢伙兒 一點技術上的小問題
Sorry, everybody. A little technical difficulty.
誰想要T恤
Who wants a T-shirt?
-嘿 夥計 -怎麼了
- Hey, man. - What's up?
我很抱歉 我還不太懂我的角色
I'm sorry. You know, I'm trying to understand, for my character,
我們難道是在表示
you know, um, are-are we suggesting, you know,
奶爸覺得一個成年男子可以給嬰兒餵奶嗎
that the Man-ny thinks a grown man can breastfeed a baby?
我們是想說明奶爸腦子有問題嗎
Are we saying the Man-ny's got brain damage?
因為我可以說點話
'Cause I could do a voice.
凱文 我知道你在意 你在意這個角色
Kevin, I know you care. I know you care about the character.
謝謝你 我確實很在意這個角色
I do care about the character. Thank you.
我還知道你是個三十好幾的男演員
I also know that you're a 30-something-year-old actor
最好的成績也不過是在《音樂之鄉》裏面露了三集臉而已
whose biggest previous role was a three-episode arc on Nashville.
所以你最好按照劇本演 或者趕緊滾蛋
So say the line or find another job.
因為相信我 你從這回到車上的這點時間裏
Because trust me when I say that I'll have you replaced
我就能讓瑞恩·高斯林 瑞恩·菲利普斯
by Ryan Gosling, Ryan Phillippe, or Ryan Reynolds
瑞恩·雷諾茲 或者瑞恩·不管誰 分分鐘替掉你
or any other handsome Ryan by the time you get to your car.
相信我 我的收視會提高的
And believe me, my ratings will go up.
瑞恩·高斯林才不用來演這些垃圾
Ryan Gosling would never do this crap.
你是對的 凱文
You are right, Kevin.
瑞恩·高斯林絕對不會來演這些垃圾
Ryan Gosling would never do this crap.
記住這句話
Remember that.
拜託你 安妮
Come on, Annie!
快去搶那個球啊 甜心
Go get the ball, hon!
嘿 老爸
Hi, Daddy!
嘿 親愛的 球在那兒呢
Hi, sweetheart! There's the ball!
你想去踢足球嗎
You want to play soccer?
-這 -她踢得怎麼樣
- It... - How's she doing?
我覺得她正在為下半場養精蓄銳呢
Uh, I think she's saving it for the second half.
她怎麼樣
How's about her?
-四個男孩被弄哭了 這個數量還在上升 -這才是我的小假小子
- Four boys crying and counting. - That's my little bull dyke.
-交換 -交換
- Switch? - Switch.
-那是 -法式辮子嗎 是的
- Is that a... Aw. - French braid. Yes.
穿上去 穿下去再穿過來 寶貝
Over, under, back through, baby!
-嘿 媽咪 -很好 至少 她交到朋友
- Hi, Mommy! - All right, well, she made a friend.
我找到他了
I found him.
我的父親
My father.
什麼 什麼時候
What? When?
我雇了一個人
I, uh... I hired a guy.
花了將近一千五百元
It cost about 1,500 bucks.
現在 你會發現我用證券的形式付給他
Now, I paid for it on the Amex. You're gonna see it.
是私人證券 不是商業的那種 我知道
It's the personal Amex, not the business Amex. I know,
-我才不在乎那些證券 -我知道
- I don't care about the Amex. - I know.
所以你要
So you're gonna...
-沒門 -為什麼
- No. - Why not?
因為我媽是一個難產而死的癮君子
Because she was a crack addict who died during childbirth,
而我爸把我扔在消防局門口
and he was the guy who left me at a fire station,
很可能是因為他想不到任何其他的好地方
probably because he couldn't think of anything more cliche.
那你還找他幹嘛
So why'd you find him?
我也不知道 貝絲
I don't know, Beth.
我真的不知道
I really don't know.
噢 加油
Oh! Go!
幹得漂亮 泰絲
Way to go, Tess!
別忘了運動精神 寶貝
Sportsmanship, baby!
抱歉
Excuse me.
你介意嗎
Do you mind?
然後我就和我自己說 坦尼亞
...and so, I said to myself, "Tanya,
你已經做了所有你該做的了
"You have done what you have set out to do.
你減掉了體重
"You have lost the weight.
現在你可以幫別人變成像你一樣的瘦子了
And now you can help others be skinny like you."
所以 誰想來分享他的故事
So, who would like to share first?
每次我準備節食的時候
Every time I'm going on a diet,
他都會來阻止我
he sabotages me.
我丈夫一次又一次在半夜抓住我
Well, my husband found me eating out of the fridge
在冰箱外面偷吃食物
in the middle of the night again the other night.
我在努力
I'm trying.
我不是阻止你 瑪莎
I'm not sabotaging you, Marsha.
我知道我的問題和在座的各位都不一樣
I know I don't have the same issues as everyone here.
但是你們完全不知道 像我這樣的人
But you guys don't know what it's like looking like me
每天帶著上半身多出來的八磅肉是什麼感受
and carrying around that extra seven pounds in your midsection.
對於我來說
For me,
最大的病因就是我媽
it was my mom.
她以前從來不讓我們吃披薩
She never let us eat pizza.
所以現在 每次我看見披薩
And so now, every time I see a pizza,
我都一定要把它們都吃完
I mean, I have to eat the entire thing.
如果再這樣下去的話 我可能
If this doesn't work, I might just
就要把我的胃釘起來封住然後
have my stomach stapled and just be done with...
對不起 各位
I am sor... I'm sorry.
我只是 只是在想像訂書針
I was just... I was picturing the stapler.
真的是
And it's...
太不合適了
which is totally inappropriate.
我抱歉
I apologize.
如果有幫助的話 我得說
I'm way fatter than you if it...
我比你可胖多了
means anything.
嗯 咖啡
Mmm, coffee.
嗨
Hi.
天 這些人討厭我
Boy, these people hate me.
你有點越界了
You kind of crossed the line.
沒錯 你也笑了
Yeah, you laughed.
-因為我是為跨界而生的啊  -噢
- That's because I live across the line. - Oh!
好吧
Okay.
托比
Toby.
凱特
Kate.
沒錯
Yeah.
很高興見到你
Nice to meet you.
所以 你想要一起當胖友嗎
So, you want to be fat friends?
當然
Sure.
-但是我一定會減肥成功的 -你知道的
- But I'm gonna lose the weight. - You know,
我大概會失敗
I'm probably not.
好吧
Okay.
我現在不能和胖子談戀愛
I can't fall for a fat person right now.
好吧
Well...
那我也去減肥好了
I guess I'll lose the weight then.
呼吸 貝卡 呼吸  呼吸 呼吸
Breathe, Bec. Breathe, breathe, breathe, breathe, breathe.
呼吸 呼吸
Breathe. Breathe.
深呼吸 貝卡
Deep breath, Bec.
深吸一口氣 呼出來
Deep breath, deep breath.
深呼吸 看著我 深呼吸
Deep breathe, look at me, deep breathe.
幹得好
There you go.
非常好 快完了 快好了
There you go, almost done, almost done.
深呼吸 嘿 幹得很好
There you go. Hey, there you go.
寶貝 我要為我接下來兩個小時內說的話提前向你道歉
Baby, I'm sorry for anything I'm gonna say in the next two hours.
我不是有意的
I mean none of it.
-有些話你肯定是故意的 -隻有一小部分
- You're gonna mean some of it. - Very little of it.
好吧
Fair enough.
我幾乎為施耐德的闌尾破裂了感到有點高興了
I'm almost glad Schneider's appendix burst.
我挺喜歡你們倆的
I like you two.
鑒於我剛認識你們倆
Now since I'm new here,
在事情變得更緊張前
I thought we might have a conversation now
我覺得我們應該要聊聊
before things get more intense.
嗯 這是個好主意
Yeah, that sounds nice.
你要聊你的孫子嗎
So, you said you have grandchildren?
不是聊這些
Not that kind of conversation.
我知道施耐德醫生
Now. I know that Dr.
跟你們聊過關於胎位的問題
Schneider talked to you about the positioning of the babies,
也預先告知了接生的困難
and how complicated this delivery could get.
我覺得我們應該
I thought we should...
不好意思 我們不想進行這方面的談話
I'm sorry, no, we're not gonna have this conversation.
傑克 我們需要談一談這方面的
- Jack, we need to have this...
我們不會就這個話題繼續聊下去
- We're not having this conversation
-因為這樣的問題不會出現 -但是我們需要談
- because it's not gonna happen. - Well, we need to talk about...
我將會帶著三個健康的寶寶
We are walking out of this hospital with
和我妻子一起平安出院
three healthy babies and one healthy wife.
-當然 但是我們還是 -我們已經特地
- Absolutely, but we still... - I have three cribs
在我們的新家裝好了三個新搖籃
at our new home that we bought specifically
-我們的三個孩子會在那兒長大 -我知道
- for our three children to grow up in. - I understand.
我媽媽已經織好了三件嬰兒連體衣
My-my mother, my mother has already knitted three onesies.
我知道
I know.
儘管她在這方面沒什麼天賦 織得很慢
And she's a slow, no-talent knitter.
而且今天恰好是我的生日
It's also happens to be my birthday today, which tends to be
也會是我們家的大喜日子 會是我的幸運日
a pretty great day in our house, a day when I get pretty lucky.
所以我需要在場所有的人都相信我
So I'm gonna need everyone in this room to believe me
相信今天這裏只會有好事發生
when I say that only good things are gonna happen here today.
事實上
Actually...
我不僅僅只是想要你們相信
I-I don't just want you to believe it.
我是要你們都知道就是如此
I want you to know it.
你知道了嗎 寶貝
Do you know it, baby?
我愛你
I love you.
嗯 我知道的
Yeah, I know it.
我知道的
I know it.
那你知道了嗎 醫生
Do you know it, Doc?
我知道我蠻喜歡你的
I know I like you.
那就這樣吧 努力讓好事發生
Let's just start there, get you what you want.
好的
Okay.
嘿 幫我把下午空出來吧
Hey, clear my afternoon?
但是先生 那個
But sir, what about...?
謝謝
Thanks.
來了來了
Yeah, yeah.
別敲啦 我一開始就聽到
Stop all that banging, I heard you the first time,
你敲門了
banging on the door.
是誰啊
Who the hell is...
我是蘭德爾·皮斯 我是你的親生兒子
My name is Randall Peasing. I'm your biological son.
三十六年前你在前門拋下我
36 years ago you left me at the front door...
等等 讓我先說完
No, hold on, just let me say this.
三十六年前你在一個消防局的前門拋下我
36 years ago you left me at the front door of a fire station.
你別擔心 我不是因為想要你的財產什麼的
Now, don't worry, I'm not here
才過來找你的
because I want anything from you.
我的養父母無與倫比
I was raised by two incredible parents,
我擁有一個溫馨的家庭 還有
I have a lights out family of my own, and...
你看到那部停在你家前面的車了嗎
that car you see parked out in front of your house?
那部車售價十四萬三千美金 直接付的現金全款
Cost $143,000 and I bought it for cash.
我這麼做是因為我任性
I bought it for cash because I felt like it,
更因為我有錢
and because I can do stuff like that.
嗯 你看 我現在過得特別好
Yeah, you see, I turned out pretty all right.
這可能會讓大家難以置信
Which might surprise a lot of folks
因為三十六年前
considering the fact that 36 years ago
我的人生始於被你遺棄在消防局門階上
my life started with you leaving me on a fire station doorstep
我除了一張破毯子和髒尿布
with nothing more than a ratty blanket
之外一無所有
and a crap-filled diaper.
我今天特意過來是為了跟你面對面
I came here today so I could look you in the eye,
親口把剛剛這些話說給你聽 然後回到我的豪華轎車
say that to you, and then get back in my fancy-ass car
是為了向我自己證明 向你證明
and finally prove to myself, and to you,
向愛我的家庭證明
and to my family who loves me,
即使我知道了你是我的親生父親
that I didn't need a thing from you,
我也不需要你給我任何東西
even after I knew who you were.
-你想進來坐坐嗎 -好的
- You want to come in? - Okay.
你有什麼想要跟我說的嗎
So is there something you want to say to me?
不然的話 我還有事要忙
'Cause otherwise, I really need to get going.
你想要我說什麼嗎
You want me to say something?
不 我跟你說了 我不需要你的任何東西
No, I told you, I don't want anything from you.
-但你來了 -隻是為了跟你說剛剛那番話
- But you're here. - Just to tell you that.
好吧
Well...
我知道了
I've been told.
你知道嗎 如果你只是想坐在這裏找借口辯解
You know what? If you're just gonna sit here making excuses...
-我沒有想找借口 -因為你沒什麼借口可找的
- Didn't make any excuses. - Because there's nothing you can say.
我沒有想為當年遺棄你而找什麼借口
Didn't say anything for just that reason.
看起來你像是想要我努力去彌補當年的過錯 這樣你就
Seems to me you want me to try to make amends so you can say,
-可以對我說「去你的」 然後摔門而去 -真是可笑
- "Screw you," And storm out of here. - That's ridiculous.
好吧
Okay.
我也希望能說 我還記得那天 但是
I'd like to say I remember that day, but...
我不記得了
I barely do.
我現在戒了毒了 但當時
I'm clean now, finally, but...
我是個街頭癮君子
I was on the streets then.
我還記得你母親臨終的時候
I remember her dying,
還記得那個小嬰兒
your mom, remember the baby.
我也想說我記得我把你拋棄在了消防局
I'd like to say I remember leaving you at a fire station,
但是我並不記得
but I don't.
這不是借口
Not an excuse.
事實上 這還說明了一些我自己都不記得的
In fact, it probably tells you something about me
自己的過往了
that I don't remember.
我是挺喜歡消防局的
I do like fire stations, though,
所以如果我非要做這種事的話
so that sounds like something I'd do
我是很有可能選擇去消防局
if I had to do something, you know?
我不知道這是不是你想聽到的
Anyway, I don't know if that's what you're looking for,
但不管怎麼樣 你可以放心
but either way, you can be sure
我經歷的一切已經讓我遭受了
this life of mine is punishment enough
足夠的懲罰
for the things I've done.
-如果你覺得我會原諒你 -我不覺得
- If you think I'm gonna forgive you... - I don't.
不 你是對的 我不過是想
No, you were right. I did just want
說一句「去你的」 然後摔門離去
to say, "Screw you," And storm out of here.
-嗯 繼續 -去你的
- Well, go ahead. - Screw you.
嗯
Yup.
你想要看看你的孫女們嗎
You want to meet your grandchildren?
等我拿一下外套
I'll get my coat.
嗨 小朋友
Hey, kid.
嘿 艾倫
Hey. Alan.
嘿 謝謝你幫我啊朋友
All right. Hey, thanks for doing this, man.
-噢 -我真的很感謝
- Oh. - I really appreciate it.
哎呀 不用那麼客氣啦
Oh, please. No thanks necessary.
他們付了我一大筆錢
they're paying me an absolute fortune.
當然了
I'm sure.
順便一提 你的那場戲不錯哦
Great scene for you, by the way.
-你看了？ -是呀
- You know? - Yeah.
跟你說吧 那混蛋用心寫的話還是能寫出點東西的
Tell ya what, when the prick wants to, he can actually write.
是的 那麼
Yeah. Well,
場上見吧
I'll see you out there on the playing field.
-是呀 -祝你好運吧 孩子
- All right. - Break a leg, kid.
謝謝你哦 先生
Thank you, sir.
嗨
Hey!
女士們 先生們 有請我們的艾倫·錫克
Ladies and gentlemen, the great Alan Thicke!
預備 開始
And... action.
噢 老天啊
Oh, for God's sake, I'm
我只是想要緩和一下氣氛
just trying to lighten up the situation here.
不 我知道了 那就是你的作風 對嗎
No, I get it. That's what you do, right?
我詼諧有趣的父親
My lightweight dad.
-兒子 -別叫我「兒子」
- Son... - Don't call me "Son."
你走吧 去做你自己的事 走人吧
Just go. Just do your thing, get out of here.
-拜託了 兒子 -我說了你不要叫我「兒子」
- Come on, son... - I said don't call me "Son."
當我看著那個小女孩 我願意為她做任何事情
I-I look at that little girl, I would do anything for her.
你明白嗎？如果有部火車向她開過來
You understand? Y-You show me a train,
我會毫不猶豫地上前幫她擋住
I'll jump in front of it for her, no question.
儘管她不是我的女兒
And she's not even mine.
我的意思是 這三十年來
I mean, you... you mosey in and out of my life
你就這樣隨意地走入又走出我的生命
the past 30 years like the way you have, I...
我不懂你為什麼這樣做 我從來都不懂你
I don't understand that and I'll never understand you,
所以你還是趕緊滾蛋吧
so just get the hell out of here.
趕緊走吧
Just get out.
我要你趕緊滾蛋
I want you to get out and this time,
並且再也不要干涉我的人生 懂了嗎
I want you to stay the hell out of my life, okay?
-兒子 -滾
- Son... - Leave!
停
And cut!
謝謝大家
Thank you.
太好了 他們認可我們
All right, they must think we did it.
-你做到了 -謝謝你
- You did it. - Thank you.
你太棒了 你震撼了全場
You were fa... you killed.
-謝謝你的參與 -太棒了
- Thank you for being here. - Excellent.
嘿 請問可以給我那個信封嗎
Hey, may I have the envelope, please?
噢 拜託
Oh, come on.
嗨你在幹嘛呢 快過來
There, what are you doing, come on, get in here.
你看 我跟你說了吧
See, I told you, right? I told you!
這真是太棒了 凱文
That's so good, Kevin.
-噢 -這感覺太棒了
- Oh... - That felt good.
現在我們只需要
Now all we need to do is just
把另一個版本快速過一遍
take a quick whack at the alt pass, huh?
噢 拜託 我們不需要另一個版本了
Oh, come on, we don't need an alt pass,
你在說什麼呢 你為什麼
what are you talking about? Why would you...
什麼 為什麼
wh-wh-what, for what?
凱文 拜託了 我們談過這個的
Kevin, come on, we talked about this.
你知道的吧 我特別喜歡這個版本 這個是我寫的你知道吧
You know? I loved it... I-I wrote it, you know?
但是 我們還是需要 需要一個稍加粉飾的版本
But, um, we just got to, we got to get a lighter version.
來吧
Come on.
我們來演一下另一個版本
Let's get that alt.
就當是為了我吧 可以嗎
For me, okay?
呃 還有 脫掉你的T恤
And, uh, lose the shirt.
脫掉效果會好一點
It's just better without the shirt.
希望大家都已經餓了
: I hope you're hungry,
因為我們給你們準備了披薩
'cause we got some pizza for you!
所有人都愛吃披薩
Everybody loves pizza!
好吧
All right,
不 這沒事的 大家不用驚慌
No, it's okay. No, no. Nobody be alarmed.
大家不用驚慌 這只是個假嬰兒
Nobody be alarmed, this isn't a real baby.
這個嬰兒什麼都感覺不到
This baby can't feel a thing,
因為所有事情都是假的
because everything's fake!
在這齣戲裏動真感情會被天打雷劈
God forbid we have real emotion in this show.
我們到底這有什麼
What do we got here?
我們有一個真正的行李箱
We got a real suitcase.
終於 我們有些真實的東西了
Finally, we got something real.
噢 不 看來不是的 你們看
Oh, no, we don't! Look,
行李箱裏空空如也
there's nothing in the suitcase!
你他媽要去哪呢 艾倫·錫克
Where the hell are you going, Alan Thicke?!
你他媽去到那兒之後
And what the hell are you gonna wear,
準備穿什麼啊 哈？
when you get there?! Huh?
這個行李箱裏他一件衣服都沒有
He's got no clothes in the suitcase!
你們知道是怎麼一回事嗎 我開始思考
You know what it is, I'm starting to think
現在是什麼情況 事實上
about things now. It's actually...
凱西 這不是你的錯 哥們
Casey, it's not your fault, brother.
這個節目那麼糟糕並不是編劇的錯
It's not the writer's fault this show is so bad.
而且還是糟糕得離譜
And it's so bad!
播出這場演出不是網絡的錯
It's not the network's fault for airing it!
是你們的錯
It's you guys!
你們幹嘛要來看這種鬧劇
Why are you watching this stuff?
對我們要求太低是你們的錯
It's your fault for demanding so little of us
現在大家都不思進取了
that we settle.
我現在感覺我的臉已經丟光了
I can't feel my face right now,
但是你們知道嗎
but you know what?
我接這個工作的時候就已經知道它是這麼糟糕
I knew exactly what this job was when I took it.
拿這些錢是我的恥辱
Shame on me for taking the money!
捧紅我是你們的恥辱
Shame on you for making me famous!
我們每個人都該感到恥辱
Shame on all of us!
夠了
That's enough.
-喂 -你在想
- Hey... - What are you...?
兄弟 我又不是準備打你
I'm not gonna hit you, man.
我不會去打你的
I'm not gonna hit you!
你在想什麼 你覺得我是什麼野生動物嗎
What do you... you think I'm some kind of animal?!
你覺得我馬上就要發瘋了嗎
I'm just gonna go nuts?!
聽著
Listen,
瑞恩·高斯林不會接這場垃圾劇
Ryan Gosling may not do this crap,
我也不會接
and neither will I.
我不幹了
I quit...
I quit.
兄弟 和你合作很愉快 我是你的鐵桿粉絲
Great working with you, man. I'm a huge fan.
嗯 跟你合作很有意思
Yeah, that was a lot of fun.
很好 麗貝卡 用力
All right, Rebecca, one more big push, now.
就是這樣
There you go...
-繼續使勁 -加油 貝卡
- Keep pushing! - Come on, Bec.
就是這樣
All right!
很好
All right.
第一個男孩已經順利出來了
First male is out,
他看起來很健康
and he is looking good!
聽到了嗎 寶貝
You hear that, baby?
我們的兒子 我們的第一個兒子出來了
We got a boy! We got a boy!
-我們的第一個兒子 -很好
- We got a boy! - All right.
謝謝你 女士
Thank you, ma'am.
寶貝？
Baby?
有點不對勁
Something's not right.
肯定有什麼不對勁的
There's something's not right.
醫生
Doctor?
麻煩給她吸點氧氣
Some oxygen for her, please?
麗貝卡 你做得很好 寶貝
Rebecca? You've done real good, sweetheart,
但是我們現在要先讓你休息一會兒
but we need to let you get some rest right now
接下來讓我來處理 好嗎
and let's see if I can't take it from here, okay?
不好意思 現在是怎麼了
I'm sorry, what's happening?
我要給她剖腹產
I'm gonna have to go in
來接生剩下的兩個孩子 趕緊吧
for the other two, people, let's go.
你老婆現在呼吸困難 傑克
Your wife is in distress, Jack.
現在 你相信我就可以了
Now, right now, you just need to trust me
還有不要擋著道
and get the hell out of my way.
不 等一下 但我
No, wait, but I'm...
-帶他出產房 -安靜
- Get him out of the room, now. - Stat.
-孩子們 -爸爸
- Guys? - Daddy!
嘿 寶貝 來輔導一下安妮做作業
Hey, babe, I need you to help Annie with her homework...
孩子們
Guys...
這是你們的 呃
...this is your, uh...
威廉
William.
這是威廉
This is William.
-你好 -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
威廉·希爾
William Hill.
你好
Hi.
我是貝絲 失禮了 我是貝絲
I'm Beth. I'm sorry. I'm Beth.
-很高興見到你 貝絲 -嗯
- It's a pleasure meeting you, Beth. - Mm.
你褲子破了個洞
You have a hole in your pants.
安妮
Annie!
噢 沒事 確實是這樣
Oh, that's okay. I actually do.
現在年輕人不都流行這麼穿嗎
Hey, isn't that what the kids do to be cool?
在褲子上剪洞
They put holes in their pants,
-對吧 -但不是那樣的洞
- right? - Not like that.
好吧 我還以為我很潮呢
Well, here I was, thought I was being cool.
等等 那這樣呢 這樣酷嗎
Wait, what if I do this? Yo, what's going...
不
No.
哎呀呀 你肯定是泰絲吧
My, my, my, you must be Tess.
-是的 -我聽說你踢足球呀
- Yes. - I hear you play soccer...
我應該提前打給你的
I should have called.
我不知道要怎麼說出口
I didn't know how to say it out loud.
-所以你就直接這樣 -我
- So, you just... - I...
我沒法解釋 寶貝
I have no explanation, baby.
我想對這個男人說的話
Like, everything I want to say
或者想做的事 都和我所做的相反
or do around this man, I do the opposite.
這就像一個糟糕的情景喜劇
It's like a bad sitcom.
就像《奶爸》或者
It's like an episode of The Man-ny
《怎麼了》中的一集
or What's Happening!!
他把我遺棄在消防局裏 而我邀請他來我們家
He left me at a fire station and I invited him into our home.
我的天啊 寶貝 你快崩潰了吧
Oh, my God, baby, you're cracking up.
爸爸？
Daddy?
怎麼了
What's happening?
-你在開玩笑 -不是
- You're not serious. - I am.
等等 你說的是莎莉·菲爾德
Wait, Sally Field?
-是啊我對莎莉·菲爾德 -嗯
- Yeah. I have a thing - Mm.
-有種特殊的好感 你能把我怎麼著 -她好像已經有六十歲了吧
- for Sally Field. Sue me. - She's, like, 60.
六十花甲正火辣 你不知道嗎
60 is the new sexy. You didn't know that?
-嗯 -等到她七十歲的時候 天啊
- Mm-mm. - Mm. And when she turns 70...
聽著
Look out,
莎莉會在她的七十歲達到人生巔峰
Sally is gonna peak in her 70s.
-嗯嗯 -我向你保證
-Mm-hmm. - I promise you.
-好的 -給您們上點甜品 有興趣嗎
- Yeah... - Can I interest you in dessert?
-不用了謝謝 -好的
- Oh, no thanks. - Yes!
-不好 -好
- No. - Yes.
- No! - Yes.
他剛剛在問
He was just asking
他給我們上點甜品的話 我們有沒有興趣
If he could interest us in dessert.
如果他給我們上甜品的話 我當然會很有興趣
I am saying that he can.
我對甜品非常有興趣
I am very interested in dessert.
我徹底著迷於甜品
I am utterly fascinated by dessert.
甜品是我的人生追求
Dessert is my life's work.
所以
So...
我們就 還是買單吧
We will just have the check, please.
-謝謝你 -謝謝你們
- Thank you. - Thank you.
我一般不愛吃意大利燴飯
I don't normally like risotto,
但如果你把它做成球狀 油炸一下
but if you put it in a ball form, and-and deep fry it,
我大概能吃一千個
I can eat, like, a thousand of them.
托比 今天晚上我很開心
I had a really nice time tonight, Toby.
-謝謝你 -嗯
- Thank you. - Yeah.
等等 什麼 不不
Wait, what? No, no, no.
怎麼了
What, that's it?
你什麼意思
What do you mean?
你不打算邀請我進來
I mean, you're not gonna invite me in for a...
小酌一杯
a nightcap or...
或者給我打個飛機什麼的
a handy or something?
-你真有意思 -沒錯
- Cute. - I am.
謝謝你
Thank you.
今天晚上我也很開心
I did have a really nice time tonight.
好吧 你可以進來喝杯水
Okay. You can come inside for a water.
-好的 -就一杯水
- All right. - A water.
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
我們已經喝了快四兩酒了
We have already had our six ounces of wine.
我知道
I know.
每四兩酒等於150卡路里
150 calories per six ounce.
-哦 -嗯
- Ooh. - Yeah.
你一直數著卡路里的樣子
You keep counting calories,
讓我很欲罷不能
and you're gonna really turn me on.
-是吧 -嗯
- Yeah. - Hmm.
你想知道一根香腸
You want to know how many, uh,
含有多少卡路里嗎
calories are in a sausage?
這種行為合法的嗎
Is... but is it even legal?
不 在這個國家不合法
No. Not in this country.
你想那什麼嗎
Do you want to fool around?
我不想
I don't.
-哦 -呃
- Ah. - Uh...
-好吧 -不是 我
- Okay. - No, I...
不 我想
No, I-I do.
只是很長時間以來
It's just been a long time
都沒有人問我這個問題了
since this has even been an option.
我懂的 我懂
Hey. I know, I know.
不 你不明白
Um, you don't.
我三十六歲了
I am 36.
我的
And, um...
身體
this...
已經不太有觀賞價值了
...is not a very pretty picture.
沒關係的
It's okay.
-不 我 -沒關係的
- No, it's... - Hey, it's okay.
嘿
Hey!
凱文 你他媽怎麼
Kevin, what the hell?
你為什麼不接電話
Why don't you answer your phone?
呃
Uh...
-我剛才在約會 -對 你好
- I was on a date. - Yeah, hi.
哦
Oh...
這就是你在胖子課上認識的那個有趣的胖子嗎
This is... this is the funny fat guy from fat class?
-你好 -對
- Hi. - Uh, yeah,
我叫托比 那叫互助小組 不叫胖子課
it's Toby, and it's a support group, but yeah.
哦天哪 等等 你就是那個奶爸嗎
Holy... Wait, are you the Man-ny?
沒錯 我就是那個奶爸
Yes, I am, Toby.
我曾經是
I... I was.
-怎麼了 -你沒看手機嗎
- Wait, what? - You didn't check
也沒看推特 臉書什麼的
your phone, Twitter, Facebook, nothing?
-為什麼 怎麼了 -你應該看看的
- Why? Wha...? - Well, you should.
-因為 -發生了什麼
- Becau... - Okay, what is hap...
-怎麼回事 -我想讓你
What is happening? I want you to know
為我感到驕傲 好嗎
you would've been proud of me, okay?
我就是藝術界正義的化身
I was the picture of artistic integrity.
我們能拍一張你不穿上衣的嗎
Could we do one without your shirt on?
好萊塢今天的大新聞 當然就是
Well, the big news in Hollywood today is, of course,
奶爸在錄製現場發飆
the Man-ny's on-set meltdown.
好好思考一下
Think about this, I'm like, you know,
這個節目這麼糟糕
it's actually not the writer's fault
其實並不是編劇的錯
that this show is so awful.
天哪 我還挺同情艾倫·錫克的
Wow. I actually kind of feel bad for Alan Thicke.
是啊
Yeah.
麗貝卡的生命體征良好
Rebecca's vitals are good.
她還要再睡一會
She's gonna be asleep for a little while,
不過她撐過來了 我們會一直密切監測她的
but she's doing fine. We're monitoring her closely.
好的
Okay.
傑克 我們沒能保住第三個寶寶
We lost the third baby, Jack.
我非常抱歉
I'm-I'm very sorry.
第二個
The, uh...
第二個寶寶是個健康的女孩兒
second baby is a girl, very strong.
第三個寶寶是個男孩兒
The third baby was a little boy,
但是臍帶纏著他 讓他無法呼吸
but the, uh, umbilical cord was cutting off his oxygen.
他在出生之前就夭折了 這是無力回天的事了
He was stillborn. Nothing anybody could've done.
我很抱歉 我現在大腦一片空白
I'm sorry, I'm... I'm not processing anything.
我的妻子呢
My wife?
她很好
Is fine.
她一會兒就醒了
And she'll be awake pretty soon.
傑克 你有兩個漂亮 健康的孩子
You have two beautiful, healthy children, Jack.
一個男孩兒 一個女孩兒
Boy and a girl.
但我們確實沒能保住第三個孩子
But we did lose the third child.
我的妻子需要我
I need to be with my wife.
你一會兒就能去陪她
And you will be.
但她現在需要睡一會
But she needs to sleep now.
你很快就能見到她 你先坐下
But soon. You just sit down.
坐一會
Sit. Sit.
你介意我陪你坐一會兒嗎
Okay if I keep you company a second?
你坐吧
Yeah.
你介意我
Okay if I...
試著說些人生道理嗎
try and say something meaningful?
你說吧
Yeah.
去年我的老伴去世了
I lost my wife last year.
癌癥
Cancer.
這就是為什麼我一大把年紀了 還在拚命工作
That's the reason I still work so much at my age.
想要消磨時間
Just... trying to pass the time.
我們走過了五十三年的婚姻
We were married 53 years.
養育了五個孩子 十一個孫子孫女
Five children, 11 grandkids.
但我們的第一個孩子在接生的時候夭折了
But we lost our very first child during the delivery.
說實話 這就是我專攻婦產科的理由
The reason I went into this field, truth be told...
五十年來我接生過的孩子
...I have spent five decades delivering babies.
數不勝數
More babies than I can count.
但沒有一天
But there is not a single day that goes by
我不在想念我失去的那個孩子
that I don't think of the child I lost.
如今我已經一把年紀了
And I'm an old man now.
我認為正是因為我失去的那個孩子
I like to think that because of the child that I lost,
正是因為他送我
because of the path that...
走上這條路
that he sent me on,
才使我得以挽救更多的小生命
that I have saved countless other babies.
是啊
Yeah.
我認為有一天
I like to think that maybe one day
在你像我一樣蒼老的時候
you'll be an old man like me...
你也會和一個年輕人這樣喋喋不休
...talking a younger man's ear off, explaining to him
告訴他
how you...
如何把生活贈與你最酸澀的一顆檸檬
took the sourest lemon that life has to offer...
釀成一杯甜美的檸檬汁
and turned it into something resembling lemonade.
如果你能做到這個 那你從醫院帶回家的
If you can do that, then you will still be...
依然是三個孩子
taking three babies home from this hospital.
只是
Just...
不是以設想的方式
maybe not the way you planned.
我不知道這算很有意義還是老生常談
I don't know if that was meaningful or senile,
但我覺得應該告訴你這些
but I thought it ought to be said.
你妻子還要再睡一會
Your wife'll still be asleep for a little while.
去看看你的孩子吧
Go see your babies.
他們等不及要見爸爸了
They're excited to meet their father.
我認為他們有個好爸爸
I think maybe they got a good one.
不好意思 我得先把女兒們哄睡著
Sorry. Just had to put the girls down.
這些人 他們是你的
These people, they're your...
是我的父母
My parents.
我的養父母
Well, my adopted.
他們就是我的父母
They're my parents.
從你一出生他們就是你的父母嗎
You've been with them your whole life?
從始至終
From the start.
一位消防員找到我
A fireman found me.
他送我去了醫院 我的父母也在那兒
He took me to the hospital, and they were there.
他們說收養我是命運使然
They said it felt meant to be.
可以說是我的幸運吧
Just one of those lucky breaks, I guess.
消防局
A fire station.
天哪 你的父母真了不起
Gee, what a thing to have done.
-我該走了 -或許你
I should get going. Maybe we could have you by
-每隔一段時間能 -不 我覺得沒必要
- every once... - No, I don't think that's necessary.
-不要覺得有壓力 -隻是我
- It's no pressure. I just... - It's just that
我
I'm...
我快死了
I'm dying, is all.
你生病了嗎
You're sick?
快死了 不是病了
Dying, not sick.
我幾個月前就生病了
Sick was months ago.
幸運的是 我的生命就要走到盡頭了
I'm toward the end, fortunately.
我不知道說什麼好
Uh... I don't know what to say.
什麼都不需要說
No, there's nothing to be said.
你讓我見到他們
It was a kindness you've shown me,
就是對我最大的善意了
letting me meet them.
你的父親一定非常為你驕傲
Your dad must've been very proud of you.
我不敢相信我在喝著這些卡路里
I cannot believe that I'm drinking these calories.
鑒於我剛才親手斷送了自己的前程
Since I just torpedoed my career,
我覺得你可以
I think you can afford an extra,
再喝個一百八十卡路里什麼的
you know, 100 calories or whatever.
-一百五十 -一百五十
- 150. - It's 150.
如果我並不比《奶爸》上的那個自己強呢
What if I'm not better than The Man-ny?
如果我最好的工作就是《奶爸》呢
What if I am exactly "Man-ny good"?
我不知道我還能做什麼
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
百老匯演員
Broadway.
我不會唱歌
Can't sing.
演AV
Porn.
哦 可以吧
Yeah, maybe.
我還得再喝點兒
I'm gonna get some more of this red.
我麻煩大了
I'm in so much trouble.
我完了
I am screwed.
你聽著 凱文
Listen, okay, Kevin...
你記得爸爸原來說的嗎
Do you remember what Dad used to say?
不好的事情發生的時候
When something crappy would happen to us?
我們感到沮喪
Whenever we'd get down,
一切都不如所願的時候
whenever we felt like life wasn't going our way?
哪一個是你的孩子
Which one's yours?
嗯 那兩個
Um... those two.
祝賀你 雙胞胎
Congrats! Twins.
天哪
Wow.
你呢 哪一個是你的孩子
How about you? Which one's yours?
其實沒有一個是我的孩子
None of 'em, actually.
挺操蛋的
Strangest damn thing.
有人把一個新生兒遺棄在我的消防站了
Someone left a newborn at my fire station.
我不知道應該怎麼辦 就把他帶到這兒了
I didn't know what to do, so I brought him here.
來一根
Smoke?
不了 謝謝你
No. Thank you.
生活確實挺操蛋的
Life's strange.
不過祝賀你
Congratulations.
謝謝你
Thank you.
來吧 凱文
Come on, Kev.
你記得的
You remember.
他當時怎麼說的
What did he say?
關於那些檸檬的話
About the lemons?
嗯
Hmm?
「你總會有辦法
"There's no lemon
可以把一顆酸澀的檸檬
"...so sour...
釀成一杯甜美的檸檬汁」
...that you can't make something resembling lemonade."
太好了 終於親到你了
Good. Now that's out of the way.